是谁住在深海的大西瓜里
Who lives in a melon deep under the waves?
海绵汤姆
SpongeTom ShortPants
彬彬有礼  举止得体
He's very well-mannered and always behaves
海绵汤姆
SpongeTom ShortPants
如果打发时间是你的愿望
If passing the time is something you wish
海绵汤姆
SpongeTom ShortPants
那就去熟食店吃个薯泥饼
Then go to a deli and eat a knish
海绵汤姆
SpongeTom ShortPants
预备
Prepared?
海绵汤姆
SpongeTom ShortPants
反向裤头村
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
客串
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
我要去上班了  小蛞
Welp, I'm off to work, Barry
我预备好了
I'm prepared
脆卷王
我预备好了
I'm prepared
早安  海绵汤姆
Good morning, SpongeTom
早安  靠谱的客人们
Good morning, reliable customers
早安  鱿鱼哥
Morning, Octward
就爱那家伙
Love that guy
你好啊  海绵汤姆
Hey there, SpongeTom
考虑到你明天就要放假了
On account of it being your day off tomorrow
我就提前让你下班回家吧
I thought I'd let you go home early
谢了  爪老板
Thanks, Mr. Claws
我家宠物小蛞一定会很高兴
My pet Barry sure is going to appreciate
毕竟今晚可以早早开饭了
getting his dinner early tonight
太好笑了  因为讲得可对了
It's amusing because it's true
请你想象
Imagine, if you will
工作了一整天  照常坐公交下班回家
taking your usual bus ride home after a long day's work
却累到睡着  坐过了站
but you are so tired
that you fall asleep and miss your stop
径直坐到了潮间带
and head straight for The Tidal Zone
而我在这里可以缩得很小
where I can be tiny
潮间带
真是的
Come on
小蛞周一上午六点
吃的食物
小蛞周一下午五点
我出门期间这些应该够你吃了  小蛞
That should tide you over
until I get back from my trip, Barry
这可不常有
Now that is peculiar
你好
Hello?
门外没人
Nobody there
小蜗  把壳戴好
Gary, put your shell on
公交到站了
My bus has arrived
我不在的时候要乖一点  小蛞
Behave while I'm gone, Barry
昨晚睡得可真是沉啊
That's the deepest sleep I've ever had
这么晚了
The time
要迟到了
I'm late
谁给门把手挪了位置
Who moved the doorknob?
我镜子怎么了
What happened to my mirror?
肥皂片
Soap flakes?
天啊  上班迟到害得我这么心不在焉
Boy, being late for work has really thrown me off my game
上班
Work
来了
I'm here
早安  海绵汤姆
Good morning, SpongeTom
是宝宝
Bob
宝  宝
上下动吗
Bob?
那我们就动了
Okay, if you insist
我以为你今天放假呢
I thought it was your day off
真好笑  章鱼哥
Good one, Squidward
是鱿鱼哥
Octward
[ awkward（尴尬的）与 Octward（鱿鱼哥）谐音 ]
确实尴尬
That was awkward
看来蟹老板给厨房门挪了位置
I guess Mr. Krabs moved the kitchen door
谁是蟹老板
Who's Mr. Krabs?
我烤架怎么了
What happened to my grill?
食材都被切碎了
My ingredients have been shredded
这面包好像被谁一屁股坐扁了
Looks like these buns were under someone's buns
来一单了
An order
该开工了
Welp, I better get to work
上菜了
Order up
你来干嘛  小子
What are you doing here, son?
你干嘛围着厨师围裙
Why are you wearing a cook's apron?
你放假期间  我都代你班做玉米卷的
Because I always cook the tacos on your day off
你明明知道的
You know that
放
Day
假
off?
我这辈子都没放过假
I've never taken a day off in my life
这单应该是玉米卷才对的
This order is supposed to be a taco
客人如果想吃美味堡
If the customer wanted a Yummy Patty
那早就去美之霸了
they would have gone to The Yum Bucket
什么
Wha
这里到底怎么回事
What is going on here?
章鱼哥  你怎么不是章鱼了
Squidward, why aren't you an octopus?
还有蟹老板  你怎么变蓝了
And, Mr. Krabs, why are you blue?
还有
And
玉米卷
tacos?
提醒你个事  我名字叫鱿鱼哥
Well, for starters, my name is Octward
是一只鱿鱼
and I'm a squid
我每周都给你放假是有原因的  小子
You know, I give you a day off every week for a reason, son
放
Day
假
off
我们还在上下动呢  汤姆
Still bobbing, Tom
你觉不觉得海绵汤姆今天有点怪
Did SpongeTom seem a little strange to you today?
他眼睛都长在胸口上了
His eyes were on his chest
不 知 道 看 哪
对啊  我都有点不自在了
Yeah, I didn't know where to look
美之霸
有客人
Customers?
怎么会去海之霸
At The Chum Bucket?
我一定是视疲劳了
My eyes must be tired
眼镜店
好了  这样看着好多了
There, that looks better
模模糊糊的  很安心
Blurry, but in a reassuring way
待会儿给派大星跟珊迪说说
Wait 'til I tell Patrick and Sandy
我今早遇到了什么怪事
what a strange morning I had
他们就在那
There they are now
派大星
Patrick
珊迪
Sandy
派大星
Patrick
天啊  能再见到你们俩可真高兴
Boy, am I glad to see you guys
介意我吃你薯条吗  派大星
Mind if I have some of your fries, Patrick?
有点干
A little dry
介意我喝你汽水吗  珊迪
Mind if I have a sip of your soda, Sandy?
太难喝了
That is off
今天整天都乱七八糟
This day has been bonkers
章鱼哥变鱿鱼了  蟹老板又变蓝了
Squidward was a squid, Mr. Krabs was blue
蟹黄堡又变玉米卷了
and the Krabby Patties were tacos
真高兴能撞见我最好的朋友
I'm just so glad to run into my best pals
派大星跟珊迪
Patrick and Sandy
谁是派大星跟珊迪
Who are Patrick and Sandy?
先生  我的名字可是派小星才对
I assure you, good sir, my name is Preston
我不认识你说的那位派大星
I know not of this Patrick you speak of
废话  我是珊米
Duh, and me am Sammy
是一只松鼠
Am I be a squirrel folk
所有东西一样还是乱七八糟
Everything is still all crazy
哈利健身房
停业
Harry's Gym?
泡夫老师骑车学校
Mrs. Gruff's Biking School?
潮菲嬉皮伯
Groovy Groupers?
暴走小哥要路过你左边
Young Man Power Walker coming up on your left
我的胳膊
My arm
抱歉
Sorry
一定要去找爸妈
Must see my parents
有爸妈  事情就能好转
Parents make everything okay
看啊  爸妈把家漆成了
Look, my parents painted their house
满怀希望的黄色
a nice hopeful yellow
又是往眼睛里喷柠檬汁那套
The ol' lemon juice in the eye trick
爸妈的幽默感真是与日俱增
My parents really have developed a sense of humor
什么事
May I help you?
你长得跟我不太一样
You look not quite exactly like me
你这位怪模怪样的朋友是谁  儿子
Who's your weird-looking friend, son?
他长得隐约有点眼熟
He looks vaguely familiar
隐隐又约约
Very vague
你们不是我爸妈
You're not my parents
你们把我爸妈怎么了
What did you do with my parents?
你们把大家都换成了
You've replaced everyone with
怪东西
weirdos
还有你
And you
以为自己能换掉我吗
You think you can replace me?
你们就只是一堆
You're all nothing but a bunch of
一堆
of
邪恶分身
evil doppelgängers
你们这群分身休想围攻我
Well, I won't let you doppel-gang up on me
欢迎光临衣尾村
"Welcome to Tankini Top"?
你们这群臭分身毁了整个裤头村
You've ruined the whole town
you darn, dingy doppelgängers
他真可怜
Poor fella
慌得晕了过去
He got so overwhelmed, he fainted
要拿他怎么办
What are we gonna do with him?
建议给他打包一份午餐
I say we give him a sack lunch
给他送上离开这里的第一班公交
and put him on the first bus out of town
同意
Agreed
一趟公交之后
裤头村公交总站
我就是在这发现他的
This is where I found him
不知道他是怎么到这来的
I wonder how he got here
我都担心死了
I was so worried
差点就要代他做蟹黄堡了
I thought I'd have to cook the Krabby Patties
看
Look
他要醒起来了
He's starting to "un-asleepen"
派大星
Patrick
珊迪
Sandy
章鱼哥
Squidward
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
能再见到你们真高兴
Boy, am I glad to see you
我刚做了场特别怪的梦
I had the strangest dream
梦见我醒来  裤头村的一切都
where I woke up and everything in Bikini Bottom was
变了样
different
而且你不在  而且你不在
And you weren't there, and you weren't there
好好好
Yeah, yeah, yeah
我们都懂  小子
We get it, laddie
快回去上班
Now back to work
你都迟到了
You're late
我预备好了
I'm prepared
设想一下
Consider this:
人人都有一个分身
Everyone has a doppelgänger
但要怎么知道
but how is one to know
谁才是分  谁才是身
if they are the doppel or the gänger?
想得到这问题的答案  就只能前去
A question that can only be answered in
潮间带吧
The Tidal Zone, eh?
章鱼哥的
强人假日
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
我一年一度的假日总算来了
Finally, my annual day off
还是个精致无比的假日
A day filled with sophistication
先吃顿讲究的早午餐  前去高档餐厅
Starting with a gourmet brunch at a fancy eatery
汤匙俱乐部
Sol de Soup Spoon
克拉肯大道
617号
克拉肯大道617号
617 Kraken Avenue
617号
强人俱乐部
一定就是这里了
This must be the place
一定不是这里
This can't be the place
你想干嘛  高档弟
What do you want, fancy boy?
我
I
在汤匙俱乐部有预约
made a reservation at Sol de Soup Spoon
但这地址肯定不对
but this couldn't possibly be the correct address
是这里没错
But it certainly is
让我带你就座吧
Let me show you to your table
欢迎光临汤匙俱乐部
Welcome to Sol de Soup Spoon
按照我们的念法就是
or as we pronounce it
强人俱乐部
The Salty Spitoon
对
Yeah
能先给你来杯饮料吗
Can I start you off with a beverage?
有没有什么推荐
Any recommendations?
要不要
How about
蓝尸寒
the Cold Cadaver
一听就有法国风情
Sounds French
这就来一杯
I'll take one
可是雷吉
But, Reg
那可是我们菜单上最强人的奶昔了
that's the toughest milkshake on the menu
用餐愉快  一路走好
Bon appétit, and bon voyage
好极了
Très bien
你怎么还能活着
How are you still alive?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我
I--
小弟
Hey, bub
没事吧
you okay?
什么
What?
我在哪
Where am I?
这是什么地方
What is this place?
你哪位
Who are you?
我是俱乐部门卫雷吉
I'm Reg, the bouncer
你到底是谁
Who exactly are you?
我
I'm
I
不知道自己是谁
don't know who I am
想必你还挺强人的
You must be a pretty tough guy
都喝了蓝尸寒还能活下来
if you drank the Cold Cadaver and lived
对
Yeah
听着确实挺强人
that does sound pretty tough
虽然你足够强人
You may be tough enough
可以荣登最强人之墙
to hang on the Wall of Toughest Guys
最强人之墙
但是鉴于你不记得自己的名字
But seein' as you don't remember your name
就只能给你取个闻风丧胆的大名了
we'll have to give you a real intimidating one
我想到了
I gots it
疯腿哥
Crazy Legs
我是
I'm
个强
a tough
人
guy
没错  疯腿哥
You sure are, Crazy Legs
来吧
C'mon
出门去
Let's blow this joint
第一件要事  疯腿哥
First things first, Crazy Legs
我们要让你开鬼火
we gotta get you on a hog
给  你可以先借我的开
Here, you can borrow mine
就用这鬼火狠狠地炸街吧
Let's make this piggy squeal
安全第一
Safety first
真不敢相信
I can't believe it
我表现好吗  雷吉
Did I do good, Reg?
可棒了
You did great
你成功伤害了十几个人
You managed to hurt at least a dozen people
干得漂亮  疯腿哥
Way to go, Crazy Legs
给我的吗
For me?
强人就得有双强脚
Tough guys gotta have tough feet
那现在要干嘛  雷吉
So, what now, Reg?
找几个小混混干架
We look for punks to pick fights with
就比如那边那位
Like that guy over there
停
有个货真价实的停车标志
A genuine stop sign
太神了
Amazing
这位交给我
I got this one, fellas
那个拍来拍去的
Camera face
不如你来拍这个得了
Why don't you take a picture of this
好啊
Okay
我准备好了
I'm ready
这味道臭得太神了
This smells amazingly bad
疯腿哥
Crazy Legs
你一击就把他给撂倒了
You took that guy out in one hit
这件皮衣是你应得的
You've earned your leather
蟹堡王
这地方一看就适合
This looks like a good place
闲混
to loiter
我懂了
I get it
这是要来到处闲混  欺负老百姓
We hang around and mess with the normies
介意我
Mind if I
吃一半再蘸酱吗
double dip?
别
No
不要不要不要
No, no, no, no, no
好耶
Oh, yeah
我就爱闲混
I love loitering
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
爱死你新朋友了
Love your new friends
你认识这家伙吗
You know this guy?
他当然认识了
Of course he does
我们是邻居兼最好的朋友兼
We're neighbors/best friends/
同事兼最好的朋友
coworkers/best friends
我这辈子都没见过这傻子
I've never seen this chump in my life
真在这垃圾堆工作  我妥妥一废物
And I'd be a real loser to work in a dump like this
一群小混混
Loiter-er-ers?
你干嘛跟这群小混混一起混  章
Why are you hanging around
with these hooligans, Mister--
章鱼哥好有男子气概
Squidward's so macho
再这么男子气概下去就开除他
"Macho" more of this and he's fired
我们来这干嘛  疯腿哥
What are we doing here, Crazy Legs?
我看咱们得来点实际行动
I thought we could use some real action
而最强人的事莫过于来点
And what's tougher than a little
私闯民宅
breaking and entering?
只有自负的傻子
Only a pretentious chump
才住在那样一间又大又丑的人像屋里
would live in a big ugly head like that
快看这废物画的这么多丑画
Check out the terrible paintings of this weenie
这废物看着好像你
This weenie looks like you
再也不像了
Not anymore
大伙快来
C'mon, fellas
一起修理这堆画
Let's fix these pics
飞物
不好
Oh no
警察来了
The fuzz
都不许动
Hold it right there
这可是公民逮捕
This is a citizen's arrest
[ 公民逮捕：指非警察的公民
逮捕犯罪嫌疑人的行为 ]
别逼我使出这玩意
Don't make me use this thing
是那个血爆王的小废物
It's the wimp from The Krusty Scab
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
我本来在给你家每晚例行安检呢
I was just doing
my nightly security check of your house
突然一清二楚地听见了打砸抢的声音
when I heard the unmistakable sounds of vandalism
我叫疯腿哥  这不是我家
The name's Crazy Legs, and this ain't my house
我受够你跟你的童话故事了
I've had it with youse and your fairy tales
办了他  疯腿哥
Go get him, Crazy Legs
不准笑了  你个恼人的陌生人
Stop laughing, you irritating stranger
你为什么不记得我了
Why don't you remember me?
你肯定记得这个
I bet you remember this
我只记得怎么使这个
All I remember is how to play this
他哪来的炸弹
Where'd he get a bomb?
炸弹
Bomb?
章鱼哥  你还活着
Squidward, you're alive
给我下去  海绵宝宝
Get off me, SpongeBob
这群恶棍都谁啊
Who are all these ruffians?
我怎么会穿着这身俗气的皮衣
And why am I wearing all this tacky leather?
我的家
My house
你们这群流氓干了什么好事
What did you delinquents do?
你们践踏了我的秋海棠
You've trampled my begonias
玷污了我的网眼小圆垫
And soiled my doilies
还毁坏了我无价的艺术品
And vandalized my priceless art
可是疯腿哥
But, Crazy Legs
那都是你想出来的主意
that was all your idea
所以说原来这就是你家吗
You mean to tell me this was your house all along?
没错
Of course it is
疯腿哥是谁
And who is Crazy Legs?
好吧  大伙打包走人
Alright, pack it up, fellas
疯腿哥原来是个无聊的老古董
Crazy Legs was just a boring old fuddy-duddy
只是后来失忆了而已
before he got amnesia
又来了
Not again
再也不见
Well, good riddance
这样洗劫民宅才对嘛
Now dat's how ya ransack a house
大家听我说
Hey, guys
疯腿哥回来了
Crazy Legs is back